Timothy Casimer Siwula

tcsiwula@gmail.com | 415-770-2770 | San Francisco, CA | linkedin.com/in/tcsiwula | github.com/tcsiwula

SUMMARY

Hi I'm Tim and I grew up in Chicago and just finished my degree in San Francisco. I am interested in working on the following technologies as a software or research engineer: Ethereum blockchain protocols, distributed systems and computational linguistics.

EDUCATION

1/2014 — 5/2017: B. S. Computer Science @ University of San Francisco

San Francisco

- Relevant Coursework: Data Mining, Software Development, Data Structures & Algorithms, Parallel Programming
- Programming Languages, Compilers, Operating Systems, Linear Algebra & Probability, Discrete Math, Calculus

EXPERIENCE

01/2017 — 05/2017: Research Assistant @ Democratize Computing Lab

San Francisco

 Contributing to an open source javascript-to-java transcompiler & code generator project called App Inventor which uses a visual block language developed by MIT with the help of my professor

05/2015 — 08/2015: Software Implementation Intern @ Independent Contractor

Phoenix

- Lead project management and training of manufacturing software installation and configuration
- Trained staff on software workflow features while interfacing between branch and parent company IT department

05/2014 — 10/2014: Science Web Programmer Intern @ Berkeley Labs

Berkeley

- Ported a linux OS and network file system to a new architecture
- Developed a front-end web application using javascript on google cloud

01/2014 — 04/2014: Developer @ University of San Francisco

San Francisco

- Supported clients and backend engineers to resolve web service requests
- Migrated existing backend software to Wordpress

PROJECTS

01/2017 — Present: Developer @ HappyCha.in - https://docs.happycha.in

San Francisco

- Deployed: private Ethereum blockchain network, PostgreSQL database, API, smart contracts.
- Configured: continuous integration with our GitHub repo to increase deployment speedup.
- Published: NPM module that called HappyChain that exposes our API to other developers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, C, R, Javascript, Python, Postgres
- Platforms: Linux, OS X, iOS, AWS, Heroku, Google Cloud
- Languages: Mandarin (elementary)